foreign
[Music]
began with the creation of man
with use of Potter's play
roughly speaking
roughly speaking I say
is not a quranic term now a mixture of
water and
and
inorganic
material
then according to the Quran Allah gave
the clay
the phone
the shape
the fashion
display this lump of clay
perspectively
engaged man
hearts
senses
and in mind particular
disease verse
232 verse 19.
and then
something of this Allah
Spirit from a last Raw
General
States it is
I love himself who designed and
perfected man
so from this quranic verses
you can summarize by saying that man
is composed of body
and so on
he worked for soul in Arabic is Nash
it's not in the word bread
man's body is physical
bacteria
it belongs to the realm of matter it
belongs to the physical world
it's very interesting how
in Surah 23 verses 12 to 15 Allah
describes how he created man out of clay
and then he speaks now not of Adam but
of mankind
the formation of this species or
the coming of generation after
generation
how the fertilized egg develops in the
womb and then how bones and flesh come
to be
but then Surah 23.
verse 15 Allah says
then you will die
so
this material aspect of man
flesh is both
we disintegrate this is a matter of fact
we see that we see bodies very sometimes
involved
to them at all wrapping and so on
that is his body which belongs
to the world of matter
he saw
on the other hand
as it were partakes of the Divine spirit
for breath of Allah
it is the highest part of his composite
nature
and this breath of Allah belongs to
Allah it is his
but it is infused in our soul and it
comes from Allah himself
it represents the highest
the most precious part
of man's composite nature
as was mentioned last time
it is this birth of Allah means Glory
feeding from this bread
it is this breadth of Allah a man which
allows mankind to know
Allah as I mentioned before Allah is so
great
nothing can understand Allah except
Allah himself
but
if we can know something about him it's
because he himself has given us this
power to know him
as it were
if we know Allah even how little we know
of Allah is because he himself has seen
to it he implanted in Us in this
capacity to know him only Allah can know
Allah
and if we can know him this is a gift
you know him through our vision and
through Revelation but
it's finite up to the certain point
it is this breadth of Allah in US
which allow us to manifest
or to exemplify in our individuals and
socialize many of those things which
Allah desires us
275 like the virtues of holiness
of being truthful or being sincere
even matters of Corporation politeness
and the virtues of patience
love
compassion
and in the sacred use of
our life
and also in the protection of Elijah to
others
we conclude healing
that it is this breath of alarm
infusing our soul
that is helped by us
in trust or rather it's something that
we ought to hold in trust it is an Amana
in Arabic
we don't own it
it is with us as alone
and therefore anything that we have as a
law
must be returned to its owner
but more than that we will be asked what
did you do without those
how did you use this breath of Allah
this power to be good
you were given many things to be good
the to use it for good
you have helped all of us are helped
accountable
therefore
as I said it's a loan and the trust and
can only in order to be used only in
terms of Allah's Commandments
I take it
that this thing
practically to us
something from the last period
is imperishable
so far
thank you so many times that when we die
for our death our physical bodies refer
to play music he was playing in a small
General sense
but don't ask me details
regarding what happens to this breath
the lineup
and Allah suggests himself in Surah 1785
this is a capable of many
interpretations and translations Allah
says that regarding the Rock
spirit
message revelation
or the bread in US
he says very
live the knowledge of that
is given to man
we know as a matter of fact that one is
focused social sciences
if I told you before psychology for
their time then
it is the least development
progress in Psychology technology
Corporation
about 100 years ago it's very very
uh employee signs if you can call it the
old design is highly theoretical and
it's very interesting Quran says
something
suggests
that these discussions about Iran
is very little it's about shaped to man
so I cannot say more on this
anyhow
it's very clear in the Quran
events have mentioned anybody verses
that all creation is for possible
when Allah creates something it is for a
certain purpose
we know some of these purpose in terms
of our minds that are given us for in
terms of Revelation but in any case
even if we do not know
why Allah that's something there must be
a reason for it
and
regarding our own creation Allah himself
reveals to us
that he created us to worship Him
now let's be very careful about reward
worship it's a translation from the
Arabic and most people think of worship
a salad
so they say well
we mix a lot so we worship Allah no
worship
is a very full translation
is due to the limitations of English
language
Worship in Arabic is not confined to
Salah or fasting and so on but worship
evolves everything that righteousness
means being also in the straight path
chiraton Kim
it means doing everything that Allah
requires us to do
and thus last time I emphasize
that worship includes the duty to
develop the capacities implanted in Us
by Allah
as connoted
or replied by his spirit to ask
something of his spirit
again this means therefore
that if God has given up the capacity to
be compassionate he becomes a duty for
us to become compassionate
if he has given us the capacity to be
truthful
if he has taught us
how to read
and giving us the capacity to read it
becomes our duty to develop our
intelligence and become security for us
to increase our knowledge
continuity for us to be pious and to you
what powers we have physical
intellectual economic political Etc we
use all of these words
it is given as the capacity without it
means it becomes a universe love but in
the right sense in accordance to the
Commandments of Allah
and that gives us must be held as an
ocean
Trust
but having a body
and physical Life as we all know and
then imply material elements to
perpetuate or maintain life
moreover
as long as our composite nature is the
way it is
man needs the body to help develop
disorder
you cannot read Quran
three or four hours at the stress in if
he does not eaten for one week
you have to
eat you have to take care of the body
and if it's freezing weather
how can you read the Quran
you need something in other words what
I'm trying to say the body needs some
comforts
minimum
needs benefits in order to perpetuate
Islam and increase its knowledge
as long as this composite nature is the
way it is
we need some material requirements in
order to worship Allah
and
a great deal of our knowledge comes from
our senses from sense experience
and indeed
it is a lot of these virtues are related
with our physiology how can you be
patient about pain
unless you have a toothache and
appreciate that's the meaning of pain
love itself involves emotion
feeling of worrying that people have
when they think of the wife and the
children all of these require a
physiological way
but I mean in particular is that many of
these qualities that we exemplify like
patience and so on so on they are
manifested in physical and material life
but for a temporary
character
Surah 21 verse 8 says specifically the
parties need food but the bodies will
put the maintaining time perfect
no one becomes very clear to all of us
why Allah who owns everything
announcement
the use of Earth
or gives him power on Earth to partake
of its provisions
this is found Surah 2 verse 29.
let me call Surah 67 verse 15 Allah says
he Allah is the one who subdued the
Earth for you
from its corners and eat from his
provisions
but now it is an important
before him he will be ultimately rather
it's very clear River says
eat
yes the Earth Earth is given to you to
take care of your bodies
to give you the material basis for the
very thing you saw
but
to him you shall return
it's very clear
go ahead
enjoy yourself on Earth but you have to
answer on that score
so life becomes a very serious affairs
Allah gives man power on Earth
and power is one of the faculties of the
Soul
Surah 7 verse 10 and I say we put you in
control of the earth and establish for
you for official
pray for them
and thus
number one giving the Earth to man
to Rome
allowing him to eat of his provisions
giving man power on Earth
or God
subduing the Earth for the sake of man
or giving man the powerfulness of the
earth which is estimated the same
and provided further that made his
health accountable in how he utilizes
such Provisions all of this is what is
meant by saying that mankind is Khalif
on Earth
Etc
the word Khalid
I'm not talking about
means
many things
it means to inherit
Department
to inherit
to succeed
to serve as a deputy
to serve as a figure
to serve as a vice region
and so on
but such a succession on Earth
such an inheritance on Earth
is not absolute
it is finite because man has to die
it is relative because
only Allah
is absolute
but the grounding of this Khalifa to man
giving him Earth
and inheritance
is really a test
Allah says
then we meet you inherit the earth to
see what you do
of course
the power of
Khalifa
is delegated power
it is a power held in trust
it is a power to be exercised in terms
of the one who dedicated this power or
who gave this power in other words
the power of
the Khalifa Earth
powers of mankind on Earth whether you
call them successors or inheritors
it is never absolute
power
so it is inheritance between God if you
inherit something from
people parents who died
then to understand
you can say you won't but you've
inherited and you can dispose of this
inheritance the way you want but when
you inherit quote unquote something from
Allah
you cannot do anything you want
he's still alive
so you inherited give me spiritual sin
unfortunately it's an English word that
we're using you inherit something from
Allah that is not dead He's Alive and
then you have to account to him all the
time how you are handling that
inheritance
and I think it's important uh to thank
all of us
that regarding the temptation of Adam
which we have over work
in our discussion
the temptation of Adam was precisely
the temptation of absolute
and power that is unanswerable
so now we can relay the temptation of
Abraham
to
man's so-called Halifax on Earth
in Surah 33
verse 72 shows clearly how the abuse of
such power the
is manifested
man shown he can be wrong
or unjust
or tyrannica or exploitative
or playing the ignorant when he
exercises the responsibility of Khalif
when he disregards Allah's revelation
or when he forgets Allah
as the Lord
as the source of all power
and as the real or ultimate honor honor
of all the heavens
Adventure
would be Khalif on Earth
was part of Allah's plan even before the
Disobedience of
of England
Surah 2 verse 30 years
Allah
informs the angel
that he is going to establish a Khalif
on Earth
he suggested to the Quran that the
Angels were somewhat apprehensive
they spoke
what Allah you send a Khalif on Earth
who is shared blood
and Allah says
you do not know what I know
land
thus
the Surah 2 verse 31
Allah
that the next person
after Allah informed the angels that he
will send it on Earth in the angels
very concerned for reasons of their own
that belong to another Buddha by the
initial ideas that were upset it see if
they were upset
he's the person 30 verse 31
the Quran reveals how Allah already
started to prepare Edam or mankind for
the Hari faith
how by teaching Adam the names
this is the training
so far all of this
qurani
I have kept my interpretation to myself
but now to remind him of generosity
allowed me to come to interpretation
foreign
qualities on Earth but in a limited
and relative money
Allah knows absolutely we have the power
to know but finally
Allah
hey
Allah is the holy the Kudos we are
supposed
we are supposed to make manifest in this
world in the world of
experience
and the angels not having bodies
cannot have this
one
and a man has a good Edge
[Music]
anyhow
whatever thing you have in your body
when you take it Allah this is part of
one's body part of the human population
but he's smart enough
Generations
but your patience
a lot is strengthen you
now the engine
cannot have that one and just don't have
if they didn't have all speakers
maybe that's the reason why the Angels
do not know
right
manifestations of Allah
even after Ada he was learning a few
things from Allah
for that huh
when he fell into the Trap of Satan's
temptation
Satan said can I show you the tree of
immoral Fatality and power that you
never pay a kingdom that will never
perish or absolute sovereignty
Adams he forgot what did he forget that
only Allah is the source of all power
that only Allah is eternal only Allah is
absolute only elasticity he's the
magical Monk foreign
[Music]
but even
he forgot
the plan to send him to Earth was never
abandoned
what did this obedience in the garden
brought immediately fast expansion
but expansion from the garden Maybe
the training
but that's not important for us now
because Allah himself promised
Revelation So Adam learned something in
the garden the names of Allah he learned
and on Earth
allies now sending revelation
in other words distractions begun by
Allah in the garden was to be continued
by means of Revelation on Earth provided
now that man was willing to listen all
his willing to listen to such vibrations
and provided man deserves such
Revelation because if you don't deserves
such Revelation Allah seals your heart
for our hearts
but in many things man stay on Earth
wants to be temporary for they must be
great for him Allah said this to Adam
that this is so in Surah 40 verse 67
here
and I say
to us you are created of dance for a
peace determine time in Spanish
but those who reject the revelations
they will deserve hell they will not be
allowed to go to the Garden but those
who follow this Revelation from Allah on
Earth they have nothing to fear
on Earth
so as khalids on Earth
to keep ourselves righteous
we will deserve the garden but only
after a second creation we will have new
bodies
Khalifa
a new body that will be able to
withstand the presence of Allah
I often believed your brothers and
sisters
that he comes originally stay in the
garden was a sort of training grounds
a place for him
he would receive a lot of instructions
from Allah and see see something in the
garden
but unfortunately our great great great
grandfather he failed in following every
detail of Allah's warning which is a
terrible lesson for all of us
maybe two we can say there was something
in the garden which Adam could have seen
and learned and to use as a mother
when he comes to Earth as a viceroid in
other words
he will try to exemplify
the
qualities of Allah
I would like to think that the world of
the garden
again
this Earth
and Hell in some ways half for one of a
better term
s that are correspondences
there is an A in the garden its
corresponds to an A on Earth which
corresponds to an a
head not in all cases but in many ways
for example there is a kind of drink
in uh
in the garden there's a drink on Earth
there is also happy
there are trees in the garden in
Paradise there are trees on this Earth
there are also trees like this
so this is what I mean by analogous
University
or Wolves
Maybe
forgive me I am speaking English too
much
the idea was to use the garden
as a model
and make life on Earth
approximate
Paradise but up to certain
limits
if this is strange what I'm saying let's
find out
in all mankind on earth now
if all of us were righteous
if all of us were
Allah kunship all the time conscious of
Allah
in accordance it is
Commandments
remember Allah standing seeking lines of
yeah
keep remembering him in every action
this is happening everybody is conscious
of Allah everything he does is in terms
of what Allah wants you to do
isn't this something